[Uhtred] I was born
an Aelderman of England.
True heir to the Northumbrian lands
of Bebbanburg.
I was 12 years old
when I first went to war.
I saw my father killed.
Stolen by the invaders,
along with a Saxon girl, Brida,
I became first a slave
and then a son to Earl Ragnar.
Fate had made me a Dane.
Had made Young Ragnar my brother
and Brida, my lover.
And then fate brought betrayal.
Fire!
Lies were thrown to the wind
saying I had killed Ragnar.
So, taking his hidden wealth,
we fled south...
...to Wessex.
To Beocca...
and to the king's brother, Alfred.
Seen by the Danes as a Saxon,
and by the Saxons as a Dane,
my word could not be trusted.
But I am Uhtred, son of Uhtred,
and destiny is all.
Stand clear, it is the king!
I have to speak, Lord.
The axe cut deep.
Even a king couldn't survive that wound.
We shall pray and we shall see.
Apologies, Lord, this is the best I could
do without first speaking to Alfred.
I have brought food and ale
and more importantly, good news.
Alfred is dead?
The opposite.
He is alive and he is victorious.
We defeated the Danes.
[yelling]
Why is this good news?
Alfred acted upon your advice.
You share in his glory.
Glory?! Then why is he caged
and left to shit in the corner?
You call that glory?
Can she not hold her tongue
for just one moment?
No, she can not and she will not!
Keep your food, I don't want it!
I will not eat or drink
until I am set free!
Only Alfred can order your release!
I will speak with him!
You should spend this time, girl,
to contemplate your improvement.
I will use this time to curse you.
Then do it!
Alfred refused my sword.
I won't be offering it again
unless he begs.
Lord, sometimes I wonder
whether your pig-headedness
is not simple stupidity.
He will send for you when he has scraped
the mud and blood from his mail.
We will give thanks to Odin
for our deliverance.
Do that!
We are Danes!
[guard] Show respect!
Do it again and I will cut you
prick to throat.
You're a hero of Wessex.
Congratulations.
We're alive.
[Alfred] What is it?
I couldn't wait to see you.
I was told you are safe,
but I needed proof.
Here it is.
Leave us. My wife will help me.
My Lord.
My privilege.
Ensure it is repaired and well.
I'd be a lost fool without you.
[sighs]
Fingers and thumbs.
[knocking]
Who knocks!?
My Lord.
My Lady.
Forgive me, I was hoping for a moment
to discuss the Aelderman Uhtred.
Father, forgive me,
but my Lord is in need of rest.
He is. You are...
Forgive me.
Aethelwold. Were you on the hill?
I didn't see you.
I was kept safe with the priests.
There will be other battles, many.
And on and on it will go, I'm sure,
until we are all dead.
You saying we should surrender?
Never... never.
But I am not against compromise.
As much as I love my God,
I am in no hurry to reach Heaven.
I fear no number
of kneeling clergy men will change
what a heathen's axe has already decreed.
Our prayers should be
with the king's successor,
whoever that may be.
The crown is mine, my birthright.
You disagree?
The argument against
will be that you are young, Lord.
I am my father's heir!
Yes, you are your father's heir,
but your father was also bonded to Alfred.
A son comes before a brother.
Then perhaps you should speak
to the king directly.
Tis my thinking, Lord,
that if on his death bed,
your father were to name you
as his successor,
the Witan would find it difficult
to go against him.
I believe your father would only be
too happy to whisper in your ear,
whether he was conscious or not.
Your counsel will not be forgotten,
Young Odda.
Thank you, Lord.
Guthrum, you went into battle without me.
Why was that?
That was not the intention.
Is that so?
Then why did it happen?
Let's talk inside.
We will talk here.
They marched sooner than we expected,
and they positioned themselves
well on the hill.
It will not happen again.
No. It will not happen again
because you have lost half your men.
We killed their king, Aethelred.
Did you see him fall?
Yeah, I saw him fall.
He took an axe. He's dead.
We were not beaten.
Hmm... you want to become King of Wessex.
I will allow that.
But where is my payment?
My silver, my grain?
It was promised, but now it has gone.
It's still there.
Danes do not lose.
I have not lost.
You have given them hope,
Guthrum, that is worse.
Without the king, there is no hope.
If they've defeated the Danes,
which I won't believe,
why aren't they feasting?
The priest doesn't lie,
despite him being a priest.
Why are they so different?
So miserable.
God's wish.
I won't become a Saxon woman.
I won't wash, work the fields,
till I drop and cook.
It won't come to that.
That won't be my life.
Alfred can help us.
We'll use him...
...for shelter and then for wealth.
He has used you.
And now he owes me.
[bell tolls]
[pig snorts]
[gasps]
Good morning.
My thanks for last night.
[rooster crows]
Open the door, I wish to see my father.
Open the door,
or I'll have your balls for sling-shot.
Aethelwold.
I am here to pray for my father,
the king; to be at his side.
The king is dead.
Why was I not called?
I should have been at his side.
You could not be found.
I was sleeping in my chamber.
Before he passed, the king
named me as heir to the throne.
That's what he told me.
It's the truth... his last wish.
His last command.
You would all do well to repeat this.
I'll inform the Witan of your claim.
You should.
Although each person here, and more,
heard your father
bequeath his crown to Alfred.
He must have been delirious.
On which occasion?
I am the son of the king.
Do your duty.
My Lord.
Ah, Uhtred.
Please accept my apology
for the delay in your release.
I had other matters to attend.
Ale, Father?
A little, and for our guests.
It seems you spoke the truth.
I did.
Though I realize our victory is temporary,
I am indebted.
Wessex is indebted.
Is my apology enough?
It's not, Lord.
What Uhtred means
is that it is not necessary.
I wish to be seen as an Aelderman.
Because I am an Aelderman.
In Northumbria. This is Wessex.
This is England.
One kingdom is what you said.
You are without lands, completely.
Then that's what I want.
That's what I deserve, land.
I brought you here
solely to convey my thanks,
but we shall talk further at some point.
Now I have other more important
matters to attend.
I gave you victory, Lord,
what's more important than that?
The king is dead.
Since when?
I have not long left him.
My first act as king
will be to offer the Danes a peace.
They will think you spineless... Lord.
Then I must convince them otherwise.
Girl, bring some fruit to my chamber.
Some chopped apples and milk.
Rest, wash, eat well.
You have earned it.
What are you saying?
You do not speak to a future king
in that manner.
He is not my Lord and he won't be my king.
Hear me clearly, Uhtred.
Alfred is the man to follow.
He is your way back to Bebbanburg,
as Lord and master.
Uhtred's path is Uhtred's business,
not that of a priest.
Forgive me, Lord!
I must leave, pray for strength
to expunge these unholy thoughts
that fill my mind.
You want land in Wessex?
It's my way back to Bebbanburg.
Any silver you find under Alfred
will be taken by the Danes,
along with your life.
They can't be beaten.
Why are you doing this?
I've said, wealth.
Excuse me, my Lord,
I am on an errand to my Lord Alfred.
The milk is for Alfred?
It is.
Not a word.
Go on.
[breathing heavily]
Master Aethelwold.
The man-child who would have
himself be king.
Out of respect for the late king,
Alfred wishes no to harm to be done
to a hair on your ugly head,
but he will not put up
with your insolence and lies.
Your own son is party
to my so-called insolence.
Quiet!
Don't you involve others
in your conspiracies.
My head is not ugly.
You're to be sent to Hampton,
to a monastery, to be educated.
It will be a very long process.
I am the king's son!
Wessex cannot afford division.
Nor can it afford the ramblings
of an idiot child,
noble or otherwise.
See to it.
May I make him docile, Lord?
I wish you would.
[Aethelwold] No, no, no, no!
[knocking]
[Alfred] Come!
Lord, you wished to see me.
I did, I did.
You will take a message
to Guthrum, to the Danes.
You will invite them to negotiate
within days
but at their own convenience.
If it is a messenger you require, Lord,
there are plenty
within the palace grounds.
It is not a messenger I require,
it is a representative.
You will speak for me.
Odda, you will speak as me.
Nothing can be written for the Danes.
My letters would be meaningless,
therefore the words spoken
must be my words,
and I entrust them to you.
Then I shall gladly be
your representative, Lord.
Thank you.
Do I offend you?
Watching you.
No, my Lord... never.
I will defend you with my life.
You stand as everything that is
precious, you are Wessex, England.
Always to be cherished,
never to be violated.
Only to be loved... vigorously.
[knocking]
Who is it?
-[door opens]
-My Lord.
My conscience.
My Lord, would you care
to join me in prayer, perhaps,
for the passing of the king?
I will, Father. I give you my thanks.
Forgive me, my Lord, the milk has soured.
I am tired of milk and apples.
I need meat.
But you are a martyr, my Lord, to meat.
My Lord needs feeding!
My Lord is not a saint and never shall be!
I have survived battle, I need meat!
We shall pray together, my Lord,
for strength.
Why does it have to be a sin?
Already, it is a burden.
It seems never to be about
what I would wish to do.
It is about what I must do.
Ask God to give me the strength
to wear the crown as well as you.
Father Beocca. A moment.
Yes, Lord.
Uhtred may well have a use.
I'm pleased that is what you think, Lord.
This Brida, she is what to him?
I would say a hindrance, Lord.
A wife?
No, no, never. No, no.
She is restless.
She is the devil on his shoulder, I fear.
But he is fond of her.
Yes, that is his way.
We shall see.
Thank you.
My Lord.
I carry a message.
From King Alfred.
Who is King Alfred?
He is Alfred, King of Wessex.
He invites the Earl Guthrum
to negotiate a peace.
You are Guthrum?
Get down from your horse, boy.
Get down from your horse and look at me.
You are a beauty.
Tell this king, what was his name?
Alfred.
Tell King Alfred that
Guthrum accepts his invitation,
and I will watch for him
and I shall ride out and meet him.
I will pass on your message, Lord.
This horse belongs to me now.
Uhtred, Alfred is keen
to find a use for you,
but Brida is...
She's not a help.
Perhaps you could just
keep her away from him.
Alfred knows how I can be of use.
-Uhtred.
-And I have proven it.
Now he must prove he can be of use to me.
He will be king.
And you can serve him.
I'm here to serve myself.
Alfred means nothing to me but a path
to take back what's rightfully mine.
My land, my wealth and my title.
He will have a use for me,
but I will have a use for him.
Do not think him naive.
He will see right through you.
He will see what I allow him to see.
Look, Uhtred, right now
you are a warrior, not a thinker.
Though in time, this will come.
You are much like your father,
and he was both.
You are Alfred's priest now, Beocca.
[man] You looking for company, girl?
I prefer the company of the gods
to stupid men.
Another time, then?
[snickers]
[knocking]
Good morning, Uhtred.
Good morning, Lord.
That's a fine coat of mail.
It is. And it is yours.
The battle dress of a Saxon warrior,
a gift.
In return for what?
There's always a price.
Which you have paid in full,
our victory at the hill.
Young Odda, have you offered
your apologies to Uhtred?
My sincere apologies, you spoke the truth.
A small bow, perhaps?
You may leave us now.
A good king relies upon
good advice, Uhtred.
For example, my nephew,
Aethelwold, the king's son.
He is young, but sees himself
as the rightful heir.
How am I to deal with him?
You should kill him, Lord,
as my own Uncle Aelfric, would kill me.
Not to kill him shows weakness.
[Odda] You are being insolent.
I will allow it,
it is the Pagan in him speaking.
You think like a Dane, Uhtred.
If I kill Aethelwold,
I am admitting he has legitimate claim
to the throne,
which he does not.
That is how I think.
But to have a specimen
of the heathen mind in council
will be useful.
What do they fear most, the Danes?
They're warriors, they live to fight.
But when they lose,
as at the hill, what then?
In battle, they'd rather retreat
than lose too many men.
So if they fear anything at all,
it's losing men.
They love to fight but hate to lose,
hardly a revelation.
-Odda appears not to value your council.
-I do not!
I care not.
I have been thinking on your request,
to be recognized as an Aelderman.
[Odda] Which is a nonsense.
I am an Aelderman.
Without even a goat to your name,
never mind the land to graze it.
I am an Aelderman by birth, Lord.
Would you perhaps consider
becoming an Aelderman by marriage?
I know of a marriage
that would bring you land and title.
I have no need of a wife, Lord.
-A woman helps you grow.
-Grow old?
Grow roots,
and that is what you are missing.
Marriage would show
your commitment to Wessex.
I have shown commitment.
You've said yourself,
I gave you victory at the hill.
You helped, Uhtred, but the victory
was won by the men of Wessex.
Whom you now refuse to join,
through this marriage.
Land and silver is what all men desire,
and I'm no different.
But believe me, Lord,
I have no need of a wife.
My sword is yours.
[Odda] At a price?
Everything that I have
has been taken from me.
I need title, I need to make my wealth.
Are you offering me your sword,
or are you selling me your sword?
To become an Aelderman,
you must possess land.
That is the law.
However, stand at my side
during the negotiations ahead,
help me read my enemy,
and in return, we shall talk further
of wealth and reward.
[gasps]
[laughs]
Well, what did you see?
What did they show you?
What I saw is my business.
[groans] I feel unwell.
Here...
Water.
Where we find ourselves is fate.
The work of the three spinners.
They sit deep in this earth beneath us
and they have brought us here.
We should go...
...to Cornwalum, Wales, Ireland.
Anywhere.
Why?
Escape.
Safety.
I saw Ragnar's ship.
The past?
No, Wind Viper.
Young Ragnar?
I was there on the ship. I saw it.
I want to leave here.
Come with me.
I've given a promise to Alfred...
...to attend the negotiations, to advise.
Brida, there's no place else for us to go.
We cannot stay here!
It's a beginning.
Leave me.
We can not wander the country
and do nothing.
How can you trust him?
How do you know he won't
simply turn you over to Guthrum,
to pass on to Ubba?
You know nothing about him!
I trust Father Beocca,
and Beocca is his priest.
I said leave me!
You were not on the ship with me!
Go to Alfred,
and I will watch him betray you!
So what do we know of this Alfred?
That he is sickly, he's weak.
He wants to negotiate.
Turns out that he's no warrior.
But he beat you, Guthrum.
[chuckles]
So, what does it say?
Negotiation.
Silver.
We will take his silver...
...and his land.
And if he refuses?
He will never refuse.
He wants to live
and he wants to be called king.
[chuckles]
[crowd murmuring]
Our God, in His Heaven,
we ask you to find favor
with your devoted servant, Alfred.
Bless him with courage,
strength and wisdom.
Never leave his side. Amen.
[all] Amen.
Allow him pure and holy thoughts
and the power to carry out your work
on this earth as our king.
Allow this anointing of Alfred
to enable your will.
You are God's king, Alfred of Wessex.
Vivat Rex Alfredus!
[all] Vivat Rex Alfredus!
[chanting continues]
[all continue chanting]
Vivat Rex Alfredus!
I can't imagine a time without you.
[moaning]
It is Guthrum?
Yes.
You can see a bone in his hair.
It's his mother's rib.
How endearing.
And the others?
It's Ubba. The big man.
The chieftain Ubba is with them?
You said he was in the north.
And now he is here.
This is good.
[Guthrum] So you are Alfred,
the King of Wessex?
I am. You are Earl Guthrum?
Yes. If you want peace,
you'll have to pay.
And you are the Earl Ubba?
Welcome.
Speak.
[Alfred] In exchange for an agreed amount
of grain, livestock and silver,
I propose that you and your ships return
to Lundene and remain there.
I further propose that
you confine yourselves
to East Anglia, Mercia and Northumbria.
Wessex is Saxon, and as such,
out-of-bounds to all Danes.
We'll not be leaving Wessex.
We only just arrived.
Then you will starve.
You have little food...
no shelter and a weakened army.
If you believe us weakened,
why seek peace?
It's the Christian in me,
the will of my God.
Oh, I will hear no talk of gods.
God. There is only one.
You will talk of grain, horses,
silver and land.
I will not talk of land.
What do they write?
[Alfred] They write what we speak.
Every word?
Yes, every word.
Then may I say arse...
tits, hump and turd?
They record history.
We are here creating history.
People will read of this very meeting.
I'm waiting to hear
the terms of your surrender.
You will be paid
for your return to Lundene.
There are no more terms
and there will be no surrender.
Guthrum, here, will not leave Readingum.
Then I say again, he will starve.
We will raid, we will kill.
And you will lose yet more men.
Is that your wish, Earl Guthrum?
To lose men.
Your surviving warriors
may look to find a new Lord.
Did you call a meeting to insult me?
I offer peace, and I offer facts.
[Ubba] His head and you can have
your peace.
Him.
Uhtred Ragnarson.
A traitor.
Nothing to say?
I'll speak to Young Ragnar.
No other Dane has my respect.
His head... for peace.
You want Uhtred here for peace.
No silver, no grain, no horses?
We want silver... and the traitor's head.
These are the terms, and you, Alfred...
you may remain king.
But we will occupy all of the Saxon forts.
If you wish to occupy the fortresses,
then do it, take them.
How many have you taken to date?
Father, how many have they taken to date?
None, Lord.
We can take all the fortresses
at any time!
We have taken the whole of England!
And we can do the same with Wessex.
Let me be clear.
I am prepared to return to the sword,
we outnumber you.
We are many and we are dangerous.
But I would prefer to establish a peace.
And Uhtred here shall keep his head,
but I will pay you well to leave Wessex.
That is what people will read,
that Alfred sought peace.
Alfred paid Lords Ubba and Guthrum
in silver in exchange for peace.
It is I, who is seeking an end
to the fighting.
That is what will be written.
Uhtred.
I would never have given you up...
to Ubba.
But the thought did cross your mind, Lord.
Not once.
The fact is, I would like you
to swear an oath,
on holy relics, a year's service.
During which time you will help
my warriors understand
that the heathens are but men.
And in return, and in time,
you shall have your own reward,
Uhtred of Bebbanburg.
One year.
[man] Boy.
For the king.
[Alfred] They have been halted
but nothing more.
[Alfred] They are not defeated.
Our task now is both simple
and impossible.
We determine what they will do next.
They will do what Danes always do, attack.
How? Where? When? How many?
We are supposed to be celebrating a peace.
Do we have to talk of fighting?
[Alfred] We do, my dear,
because the peace will not last.
It'll take them at least a year
before they can gather
a second great army.
-Do we have your word?
-[Odda] Son.
Is there any meat here?
Should she even be here?
Brida is my guest.
You should have taken up
the king's offer of a wife, a lady.
[Alfred] What happens next, I believe,
is that they will come by land and sea.
They will split our army in two,
possibly more.
Now Uhtred may be correct,
this may not occur for a year or more,
but what is clear is that we need ships.
We are bordered by water
yet we have so few ships.
You'll not get me on a ship.
I'll volunteer my son.
To save our shores,
we have to look beyond them.
And to serve God... his word must travel.
Amen. Praise him.
Uhtred, the beasts
on the prows of Danes ships,
they are a representation of their gods?
No, Lord. They are just beasts.
They can be lifted from their posts,
so not to frighten
the spirits of the land.
Spirits of the land.
I would like to know why some of them
make their own teeth into points.
They do that?
Some, lady.
God save us.
To show that they aren't afraid.
If they can inflict
such pain on themselves,
think what they might do to a Saxon.
[Alfred] We will understand them
more by the day, I'm sure.
Uhtred-of-the-Danes has promised me
a year of his service.
Is that so?
It is.
It will be his responsibility
to show our warriors
how the Danes approach battle,
the construction of their shield wall
and the like.
Lord, if I may.
The arseling here is barely a man.
You expect him to teach me how to fight?
Leofric, I expect him
to teach you nothing.
Whip him with staves in practice,
by all means.
Thank you, Lord.
But our lesser men,
if they can know what a Dane knows...
...fear can be expelled with knowledge.
Regardless how sharp their teeth.
You didn't eat tonight.
I'd only throw it up.
A year?
[sighs]
It starts with a year
and becomes a lifetime.
And he offered you a wife?
I have no need of a wife.
Instead you swore an oath to kill Danes.
You know my reasons.
We have been living in a palace.
What happens if you find yourself
facing Young Ragnar... in battle?
We fight.
[indistinct chatter]
Where is she?
I haven't heard her at all morning.
She'll not be far.
Well, were about to leave.
I can see.
I'll follow.
[groaning]
[Uhtred] Brida!
Brida!
Brida?
Almost a child.
You knew?
Hmm?
That you were carrying?
No.
You didn't see it in your dreams,
when you drank the mushroom ale?
[sighs]
I'll bury it.
We'll bury it, it's a sign of a passing.
Stand together!
[Uhtred] Shields front!
Shields up!
Shields together!
-Look them in the eye!
-Closer together! Unbreakable!
-[Leofric] Are we ready?!
-[all cheering]
I say, are we ready?
[man] Forward!
-[all shouting]
Kill the bastards!
Stand together!
[all shouting]
[grunting]
[Uhtred] Shields together!
We hammer them with our shields!
They are our defense and our weapon!
We knock them off their feet!
We're a wall!
[all grunting in unison]
Charge!
Before the two walls meet,
the first three rows of men act together
to create a tall shield wall.
First row crouches lower,
protecting the lower body and legs.
The second row reaches forward,
protecting the upper body.
The third row leans in protecting
the head of all rows of men.
Shields up!
Shields together!
Shield wall!
I like it, arseling. I do.
Now kill the bastard!
[all shouting]
[digging]
[horse approaching]
The wealth isn't mine.
It belongs to Lord Ragnar the Fearless.
You will do well to leave me alone.
[man] Are you Brida?
Who asks?
[indistinct chatter]
Brida.
What of her?
I'm no seer, but I'd say she's unhappy.
She prefers the company of Danes
to Saxons.
Nothing wrong in that.
She's been with the wrong Saxons.
The Danes have a hunger for life.
Don't we all?
Alfred... he's serious.
[scoffs]
A pious bastard.
Dislike him, by all means,
but never underestimate him.
He is ruthless.
And the man thinks...
which is more than you or I could do.
Leofric the Warrior, may I sit with you?
No, you may not.
Do the monks know you're missing?
Uhtred, this is Aethelwold,
another arseling.
Nephew of the king.
No, I am not the nephew of the king.
I am the king.
But Alfred likes to pretend,
and every bastard
appears to be happy with the lie.
[chuckles]
What are we talking about?
Alfred.
He will not allow me to fight!
Have I told you that?
Many times.
Well, it's true.
He will not allow me to fight.
I would like you, Warrior Leofric,
to teach me how to fight,
and I shall teach you how to...
Go on.
You will not forget to pay for this.
Have I ever?
Once or twice.
Alfred was caught humping a nun once.
[choking]
What I ought to do is slit his gizzard.
Say that to anyone but me, boy,
and you'll be hanged.
You are hurting royalty.
You are lucky
Alfred hasn't had you killed.
God will not allow him.
I like God.
[Uhtred makes clucking sound]
The silver?
Yes.
Why?
Are you leaving me?
Are you drunk?
Maybe a little.
We will give the silver to Young Ragnar.
Tomorrow, dusk.
He's here.
We can tell him the truth...
and we can join Ragnar and his men.
I need men bound to me by God,
by duty, by the land, by Wessex itself.
I would again like to put to Uhtred
the prospect of marriage.
To my goddaughter?
To Mildrith, yes.
Well, it would certainly bind him
to the land
and indirectly, to the church, to God.
It would test him.
It would.
You would be in favor, still?
Of course, anything for Wessex.
[birds chirping]
Uhtred Ragnarson is a good man to be.
Look at me.
You owe Alfred nothing.
To him your word means nothing,
you're a Pagan.
Please.
Uhtred Ragnarson can never become
Uhtred of Bebbanburg.
Never.
[rustling]
Did you kill my father?
Do you need to ask?
Did you kill my family?
He didn't.
I'm speaking with Uhtred!
I won't ask a second time.
If you believe that
I would kill our father,
our mother and our family...
...take your revenge.
I knew it. I knew it.
I had to be sure, I knew it.
[breathes deeply]
It was Kjartan.
Kjartan attacked and set the fire.
If we could have saved them,
we would have.
I knew it.
I didn't believe a word I was hearing.
We have Ragnar's wealth,
we kept it for you.
[chuckles] Brida.
Fully grown woman now!
I've seen this moment in my dreams
so many times.
[Young Ragnar] So, Kjartan's story
is that the English
rose against our father,
encouraged by you.
He claims to have revenged himself
for the killers.
[soft chuckle]
Did you ever believe him?
[chuckles]
Never.
But he is Lord Kjartan now.
He has three times the men
and the ear of Ubba.
When I kill him,
it will need to be planned.
When we kill him.
It will be dangerous.
It must be done.
Ragnar, we're with you.
Then you will sail with me?
I will.
I have sworn to Alfred.
It means nothing.
Well, if you have sworn...
...then you must keep your word.
I need this revenge like I need water.
When the time is right,
I swear I'll be with you.
I know.
I can't believe I'm about to let you go...
...lose you.
You have been half my life...
...all of my madness.
Be happy.
[Leofric] I take it she has gone, then?
I'm guessing that it's Alfred
that kept you here.
I sold myself...
...for a mail coat and helmet.
That's what we do, we sell ourselves.
This year, what you've giving to Alfred,
it's not about a mail coat.
It's about you.
The bastard thinks, didn't I say?
He wants more than a year's service.
He wants you to help take back England.
All of England.
Of course, when the year's up,
you could go back to the Danes.
That would at least give me
the chance to kill you.
But what would you be?
Who would you be?